Register of the Jerry Allan Rose papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Jerry Allan Rose papers
1945-2013
1959-1965
2015C51
Hoover Institution Archives
18 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 5 card file boxes (10.5 linear feet)
The Jerry Allan Rose papers consist of Rose's personal and work related materials, including writings, correspondence, notes, reports, studies, printed matter, and audiovisual materials. A majority of the materials relate to the Vietnam War and to political and social conditions in Vietnam and elsewhere in Southeast Asia.
Rose, Jerry Allan, 1933-1965.
Rose, Mary Kay.
Access
The collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2015.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Jerry Allan Rose was an American journalist and writer and was a member of the United States Operations Mission to Vietnam, which ran from 1950 to 1954.
Born in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, on December 16, 1933, and raised in Gloversville, New York, Rose started his career with the Asia Foundation in Vietnam, where he taught English literature at the University of Hue. He was later hired as a correspondent for Time Magazine and worked with various news outlets including The Saturday Evening Post, The New York Times, The Washington Post, and The New Republic. He focused on non-fiction articles, covering topics such as the Vietnam War and its effects on peasants living in the Vietnam countryside. Rose also wrote poetry and fictional short stories, submitting them to various publications. In 1964, Rose took a leave of absence from professional journalism to serve as advisor to Prime Minister Phan Huy Quat.
In April 1962, Rose married Mary Kay Peterson, a secretary at the U.S. Embassy. Together they had two children, daughter Thorina and son Eric Morrow. Although Rose was often in Vietnam and other Southeast Asian countries for work, the Roses' permanent residence was in Hong Kong. Rose passed away on September 16, 1965, at the age of 31 in an Air Vietnam plane crash on a flight inspecting refugee camps.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Jerry Allan Rose papers consist of Rose's personal and work related materials, including writings, correspondence, notes, reports, studies, printed matter, and audiovisual materials relating to the Vietnam War and to political and social conditions in Vietnam and elsewhere in Southeast Asia. Rose's writings include both non-fiction and fiction works, such as articles, short stories, and poetry. Also included are various materials relating to Rose, which were compiled by his wife, Mary Kay Rose.
Vietnam War, 1961-1975.; Vietnam--Politics and government--1945-1975.; Southeast Asia--Politics and government.; Journalists.
- Biographical File, 1959-2013, undated
  Scope and Contents note
  Comprised of personal items and documents belonging and related to Jerry Allan Rose and his wife Mary Kay Rose, including passports, certifications, obituaries, and items found on Jerry Rose at the time of his death, arranged chronologically.
  - Passport and vaccination certifications, 1959-1963 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Obituaries and remembrances, 1965 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Personal items, circa 1965-2013
    Contains personal items belonging to Jerry Rose, including those found on him following the plane crash on September 16, 1965, that ended his life. Also included is a letter addressed to Rose's daughter Thorina from Ted Engelmann regarding the items found at the crash scene.
    - Passport and plane tickets, circa 1965 (Box-folder 1: 3)
    - Wallet, circa 1965 (Box-folder 1: 4-5)
    - Letter to Thorina, 2013 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - The Saturday Evening Post, Vol. 238, No. 22, 1965 (Box-folder 23: 1)
    Includes a remembrance of Jerry Rose written by Malcolm W. Brown from the American Broadcasting Company following Rose's death.
  - The Reporter, Vol. 34, No. 1, 1966 (Box-folder 1: 7)
    Includes an article written by an unnamed author titled "Vietnam Diary: Notes from the Journal of a Young American in Saigon," which mentions Rose and his death.
- Journals, 1959-1965, undated
  Comprised of Rose's journals, which include notes and studies of various countries and topics. The majority of the journals were written during Rose's travels to various countries, including Australia, Hong Kong, the Philippines, and Vietnam. Other journals focus on his writings, artwork, and general notes. Materials with titles indicating formats such as photography, slides, or brochures are solely notes and do not actually contain any special formats. The majority of the titles are original titles that have been retained; these are indicated by quotation marks around the title.
  - Artwork, undated (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Artwork and short stories, 1956 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Artwork and sketches, undated (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - The Asia Foundation tourism correspondence and reference materials, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - Book outlines, undated (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - Communist China notes, 1964 (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - Indonesia notes, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - "Memories & Daily Notes,", 1964-1965 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Military notes, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - "These Worlds, This Time," short story draft, undated (Box-folder 2: 4)
    General note
    See also: Writings
  - Vietnam - "Johnson Taylor Marines,", undated (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Vietnamese peasants and countryside conditions, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - "Vietnam General Notes,", 1963-1964 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - "Vietnam, Oct. 1964 'The Boondockers,'" (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - "Vietnam, 1 March 1965," (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - Vietnam and American relations, 1965 (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - "VN Sout[h] Notes,", 1965 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - Pocket journals, 1960-1965, undated
    - "The American Role in Vietnam,", undated (Box 19)
    - Australia, 1963, undated
      - Australia [general notes], 1963, undated
      - "American Immigrants,", 1963
      - "Great Barrier Reef,", 1963
      - "Townsends,", 1963
      - "Wee Waa,", 1963
    - "Background Pre-Republic,", undated
    - "Burma,", 1962
    - "Cambodia,", 1963
    - "Cambodia - Vietnam,", 1963
    - "Chinese Food,", undated
    - "Color Slides,", undated
    - Contacts, undated
    - "Experimental Photography,", 1962
    - Finances and military notes, undated
    - "Furniture & Jewelry,", undated
    - General notes, 1960-1964, undated (Boxes 19-20)
    - "Good Humor,", 1963 (Box 20)
    - Hong Kong, 1962
      - "Business,", 1962 March-May
      - "Kadoorie,", 1962 September
      - "Kadoorie & Business,", 1962 September
      - "Japanese-Chicom Trade Opium,", 1962 October
      - "Concubines,", 1962 September-November
      - Hong Kong [general notes], 1962 December
    - "Hotung Brochure,", undated
    - "Immigrants & Other Australian Notes,", undated
    - Indonesia, 1963, undated
      - "Expenses,", undated
      - "Indonesia" [general notes], 1963 (Boxes 20-21)
    - "An Introduction to American Literature for Foreign Students,", undated (Box 21)
    - Kite notes, undated
    - "Laos,", 1963
    - "Laos - Satevepost,", 1963
    - Military notes, undated
    - "Notes on VN. N." [North Vietnam], undated
    - Philippines, 1962
      - "Economy & Sacadas,", 1962 May
      - "Soriano Story,", 1962 May
      - "Sugar Sacadas,", 1962 May
      - "Philippines" [general notes], 1962 September-October
    - "Photography Reference,", undated
    - "Reference Addresses,", undated
    - Research notes, undated
    - Shanghai, undated
    - "Suggest,", undated
    - "Taiwan - Economy,", 1962
    - Thailand, 1962-1963, undated
      - "Peace Corps,", 1962
      - "Thailand" [general notes], 1963, undated
      - "Opium Smuggling,", 1962 (Box 22)
    - Vietnam, 1961-1965, undated
      - "Vietnam" [general notes], 1961-1965, undated
      - "Strategic Hamlets, Operation Sunrise, Military Distribution, Education, Vietnamese Party Names,", 1962 June-August
      - "Harkins, Military-General,", 1962 June-August
      - "Montagnards,", 1962 August
      - "Gen. Westmoreland,", 1964 May
      - "The Boondockers,", 1964 November
      - "Hue hospital,", 1964 March 3
    - "West New Guinea,", 1962
    - Writings and artwork, undated
- Correspondence, 1958-1968
  Includes correspondence addressed to or written by Jerry or Mary Kay Rose, divided into three categories: career, publishing, and personal.
  - Career, 1959-1965
    Contains correspondence related to Rose's military career and work with The Asia Foundation, arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Correspondence related to Rose's writing is located in the Publishing subseries.
    - Amcocast, 1962 (Box-folder 3: 1)
    - The Asia Foundation, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 3: 2)
    - "Business Letters,", 1961-1965 (Box-folder 3: 3-5)
    - United States Operations Mission (USOM) business letters, 1965 (Box-folder 3: 6)
      See also: Career File, United States Operations Mission (USOM) file.
  - Publishing, 1960-1968
    Arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Includes letters to Mary Kay Rose.
    - ABC, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 3: 7)
    - Brandt and Brandt, 1962-1966 (Box-folder 3: 8)
    - "Copies,", 1961 (Box-folder 3: 9)
    - Lucy Kroll Agency, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 3: 10)
    - The New York Times, 1961 (Box-folder 3: 11)
    - PIX Incorporated and Playboy, 1963-1966 (Box-folder 3: 12)
    - The Saturday Evening Post, 1962-1965 (Box-folder 3: 13-14, 4: 1)
    - Time Inc., 1961-1962 (Box-folder 4: 2-7)
    - "Publishers,", 1961-1965 (Box-folder 4: 8-10)
    - "Various Publishers - Reported to be Alive,", 1964-1968 (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - "Westmoreland Photo Captions,", 1964 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - Personal, 1958-1965
    Consists of letters from Rose's life, excluding those related to his career and writing, arranged chronologically. A majority are from friends and family, but financial letters are also included. Includes letters Jerry and Mary Kay Rose wrote to each other while Jerry Rose was away from home working in Vietnam as a correspondent.
    - "Letters from before Vietnam,", 1958-1959 (Box-folder 5: 3)
    - "Letters: A-M,", 1959-1961 (Box-folder 5: 4)
    - "Letters: N-Z and Official Letters,", 1959-1961 (Box-folder 5: 5)
    - "Financial Letters,", 1960-1962 (Box-folder 5: 6)
    - General, 1961-1965 (Box-folder 5: 7-8, 6: 2-3)
    - Letters from Jerry to Kay, 1961-1965 (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - "Outgoing Letters,", 1961-1964 (Box-folder 6: 4)
    - "Letters Received,", 1963-1964 (Box-folder 6: 5)
- Writings, 1956-2004, undated
  Consists of various outlines, drafts, and edits of work written by Rose, the bulk of which are works of fiction. Arranged chronologically, then alphabetically by title. See Printed Matter for publications which include published versions of Rose's writings.
  - Bibliography, undated (Box-folder 6: 6-7)
  - "Blow, Bugle, Blow," short story, undated (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - "Book Project Outline on Vietnam,", undated (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - "The Cave," short story, undated (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - Character development, undated (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - "Character Studies for In-Work Characters,", undated (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - "Characters - Donald Woodman,", undated (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - "The Chessplay," short story, undated (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - Fiction drafts, undated (Box-folder 7: 7-8)
  - "The Fount," short story, undated (Box-folder 7: 9)
  - "The Great Debate of Educatus," short story, undated (Box-folder 7: 10)
  - "Land of the Sea," short story, undated (Box-folder 7: 11)
  - "The Predators," short story, undated (Box-folder 7: 12)
  - "Short Story Ideas,", undated (Box-folder 7: 13)
  - "A Story in Laos," short story, undated (Box-folder 7: 14)
  - Studies of Vietnam, undated (Box-folder 7: 15)
  - "Tape Transcripts - Vietnam Notes for Novel,", undated (Box-folder 7: 16)
  - "The Transients," short story, undated (Box-folder 7: 17)
  - Untitled fiction, undated (Box-folder 7: 18)
  - "Tran Duy," short story, 1956 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - "The Moon and the Street-Lamp," short story, 1957, undated (Box-folder 8: 2-3)
  - "Out of the Silence," short story, 1958-1960 (Box-folder 8: 4-5)
  - "The Falls," short story, 1959 (Box-folder 8: 6)
  - "From Use Alone," short story, 1959 (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - "Submitted Poetry and Short Stories,", 1959-1960 (Box-folder 8: 8)
  - University of Hue yearly report, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 8: 9)
  - "The Sound of Breaking," short story, 1960-1961, undated (Box-folder 8: 10-11)
  - "The Light Is as Darkness," short story, 1961 (Box-folder 8: 12)
  - "Sampan, The Freeway," short story, 1961 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - Short stories, 1961-1964, undated (Box-folder 9: 2-4)
  - Article drafts, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 9: 5-8)
  - Poetry, 1962 (Box-folder 9: 9)
  - Vietnam peasant article, 1962, undated (Box-folder 9: 10-11)
    Includes draft material, correspondence, and photographs of Vietnamese peasants.
  - Drafts and submissions, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 9: 12)
  - "Storm Clouds of Malaysia," short story, 1963 (Box-folder 9: 13)
  - "Submitted Articles,", 1963 (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - "Story Suggestions,", 1963-1965 (Box-folder 10: 2)
  - Reported to Be Alive by Grant Wolfkill (1964), 1964-1966
    Jerry Rose worked in conjunction with Grant Wolfkill on this work.
    - Bound typescript, 1964 (Box-folder 10: 3)
      Includes notes, edits, and personalized inscription from Grant Wolfkill to Jerry Rose.
    - Publication contract, 1964 (Box-folder 10: 4)
    - Book reviews, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 10: 5)
  - "The Way to the Temple," short story, 1964-1969, undated (Box-folder 10: 6-12)
  - "Ideas,", 1965 (Box-folder 11: 1)
  - "The Osprey," short story, 1965 (Box-folder 11: 2)
  - "Pham Sào Nam Di Nhi Tôí," short story, 1965 (Box-folder 11: 3)
  - All Kinds of Heroes, 1991 (Box-folder 11: 4-5)
    A compilation of excerpts from journals kept by Rose during his time in Vietnam. Compiled and edited by Rose's sister, Lucy Rose Fisher, and published posthumously.
  - Karnow plagiarism case, 1962, 2002-2004
    In 2002, Mary Kay discovered that American journalist Stanley Karnow plagiarised Jerry Rose's article "The Peasant Is the Key to Vietnam," published in the April 8, 1962 issue of The New York Times Magazine. Karnow passed off Rose's material as his own in his book Vietnam: A History, published in 1983.
    Includes Mary Kay's collection of source material, including Jerry's notes and correspondence related to his article. Extra copies of important documents were made as back up source material. Also includes Mary Kay's research, featuring clippings regarding plagiarism, and drafts of letters written to Malcolm Browne, John McCoy, and Penguin Books USA Inc.
    - Source material, 1962 (Box-folder 11: 6)
    - Plagiarism clippings and articles, 2002-2004 (Box-folder 11: 7)
    - "Kay's Back Up Material,", 2003 (Box-folder 12: 1)
    - Correspondence, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 12: 2 - 4)
- Writings by Others, 1957-2006
  - Articles by Stanley Karnow, 1998-2006 (Box-folder 12: 5)
    See also The Saturday Evening Post articles in clippings section of Printed Matter.
  - Poems by John Haag, 1957-1959 (Box-folder 12: 6)
  - Reports by Takashi Oka, 1959-1966 (Box-folder 12: 7)
    Unpublished reports on Vietnam written by Rose's friend, Takashi Oka, likely collected by Mary Kay.
- Career File, 1959-1965
  Contains materials from Rose's time as a member of the United States Operations Mission to Vietnam and as a teacher in Vietnam with The Asia Foundation, arranged chronologically.
  - Address book, undated (Box-folder 12: 8)
  - Business cards, undated (Box-folder 12: 9-10)
  - Stationery, undated (Box-folder 12: 11)
  - The Asia Foundation, "Travel Information,", 1959-1961 (Box-folder 12: 12)
  - Teaching materials on Vietnam politics and coup d'etat, 1960 (Box-folder 12: 13)
  - Expense accounts, 1960-1965 (Box-folder 12: 14)
  - United States Operations Mission in Vietnam (USOM) materials, 1962-1965
    - "Operation Sunrise,", 1962 (Box-folder 12: 15)
    - Invoices and financial documentation, 1965 (Box-folder 12: 16)
    - Memos, 1965 (Box-folder 13: 1-4)
  - Student military training, 1965 (Box-folder 13: 5)
    These materials were likely compiled by Rose during his time working as an advisor to Prime Minister Phan Huy Quat in 1965.
  - U.S. Information Service Press Branch special reports, 1965 (Box-folder 13: 6)
- Reference Material, 1956-1965, undated
  Consists of Rose's reference and research materials compiled throughout his time and career in Vietnam, including reports, clippings, notes, booklets, press releases, and index cards, arranged alphabetically by topic. Original file names have been maintained when present and are indicated by quotation marks around the title.
  - Bibliography, undated (Box-folder 13: 7)
  - "Cabinet Ministers - Decrees, Actions, Plans,", 1965 (Box-folder 13: 8)
  - "Cabinet Ministers - Visits with the People,", 1965 (Box-folder 13: 9)
  - "Cam-Ranh Bay and Nha Trang Port,", 1965 (Box-folder 13: 10)
  - "Cambodia,", 1960-1961 (Box-folder 13: 11)
  - "Chief of State,", 1965 (Box-folder 13: 12)
  - "Economic Statistics,", 1965 (Box-folder 13: 13)
  - "Faculty of Medicine, Hue,", 1964 (Box-folder 13: 14)
  - "Foreign Affairs,", 1965 (Box-folder 13: 15)
  - "Government Actions,", 1965 (Box-folder 13: 16)
  - "Government and Military Officials,", 1965 (Box-folder 13: 17)
  - Indexes, 1961 (Box-folder 13: 18)
  - Madam Ngo Dihn Nhu addresses for Vietnamese Women's Day, 1956-1961 (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - "Military and Politics,", 1965 (Box-folder 14: 2)
  - "Miscellaneous articles on Vietnam,", 1965 (Box-folder 14: 3)
  - "Miscellaneous Asian events, statements,", 1965 (Box-folder 14: 4)
  - "Miscellaneous events in Vietnam,", 1965 (Box-folder 14: 5)
  - "National Legislative Council,", 1965 (Box-folder 14: 6)
  - "North Vietnam,", 1961 (Box-folder 14: 7)
  - "Peasant Protest in South Viet Nam" draft, undated (Box-folder 14: 8)
    Preliminary draft of a journal article written by Joseph J. Zasloff from the University of Pittsburgh.
  - "Political Events in Vietnam,", 1965 (Box-folder 14: 9)
  - "Politics and Economy in Vietnam,", 1957-1962 (Box-folder 14: 10)
  - "President of the Republic,", 1961 (Box-folder 14: 11)
  - "Prime Minister - Decrees, Actions, Plans,", 1965 (Box-folder 14: 12)
  - "Prime Minister - Speeches,", 1965 (Box-folder 14: 13)
  - "Prime Minister - Visits with the People,", 1965 (Box-folder 14: 14)
  - "Programs for Land Reform,", 1965 (Box-folder 14: 15)
  - "Radio Vietnam,", 1964-1965 (Box-folder 14: 16)
  - "South Vietnam,", 1961-1965 (Box-folder 15: 1)
  - "Television in Vietnam,", 1964-1965 (Box-folder 15: 2)
  - "U.S. Actions,", 1965 (Box-folder 15: 3)
  - "U.S. Statements,", 1965 (Box-folder 15: 4)
  - "Vietnam Press Excerpts,", 1962-1963 (Box-folder 15: 5-6)
  - "Vietnamese Language,", 1958 (Box-folder 15: 7)
  - "War Events,", 1965 (Box-folder 15: 8)
  - "War Statistics,", 1965 (Box-folder 15: 9)
  - "Weekly Military Reports,", 1963 (Box-folder 15: 10-11)
- Photographs, undated
  Contains a photo album and photographs taken by Rose during his time in Vietnam relating to Vietnamese peasant life during the Vietnam War.
  - King Norodom Sihanouk of Cambodia (Box-folder 15: 12)
    Contains photographs of an unidentified man, possibly a Vietnamese government official, visiting peasants in Vietnam.
  - Album (Box 24)
- Audiovisual Material, 1963-1965, undated
  Contains sketches and artwork created by Rose, including designs for jewelry, dresses, and furniture. Also includes sound tape reels, both personal and professional, of letters and interviews with various individuals.
  - Sketches, 1963, undated (Box-folder 16: 1-3)
  - Sound tape reels, 1964-1965, undated (Box 25)
    The majority of the tapes consist of recorded letters between Jerry and his wife, Mary Kay, and daughter, Thorina, arranged chronologically. Item titles have been transcribed directly from the original descriptions written by Mary Kay on the audio tape boxes.
    - "Jerry's May 13 letter,", undated
    - "Jerry's Notes in Hue/Brief Conversation with Simone in French,", undated
    - "Jerry: Aug letter,", undated
    - "Letter: 2 April,", undated
    - "Letter: 10 April,", undated
    - "Letter: 23 May,", undated
    - "Letter: Jerry's 13 May/Thorina & Me Sept 12,", undated
    - "Jerry with Thorina,", 1964-1965
    - "Letter: 21 July 1965 (From Kay with Thorina),"
- Printed Matter, 1945-2006, undated
  Consists of magazines, clippings, books, booklets, and pamphlets. Included are copies of publications featuring articles written by Rose, as well as clippings of his published articles. Organized by printed matter type and arranged alphabetically, except for clippings, which are arranged chronologically.
  - Publications featuring works by Rose, 1958-1965
    - The Asia Magazine, 1964 (Box-folder 23: 2)
      Includes Vol. 4, No. 19, featuring "It's Rocket Firing Time in Laos" and Vol. 4, No. 23, featuring photographs taken by Rose in "The Anguish of War."
    - Audience, Vol. 5, 1958 (Box-folder 16: 4)
      Includes short story "The Leeches."
    - Clippings, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 16: 5)
    - Current, No. 43, 1963 (Box-folder 16: 6)
      Includes a short passage "Should We Threaten Ho Directly?"
    - IPS Contact Sheet, No. 2, 1963 (Box-folder 16: 7)
      Includes a short passage titled "Viewpoint: Vietnam, A Picture Editorial."
    - Life magazine, Vol. 57, No. 20, 1964 (Box-folder 23: 3)
      Includes photos taken by Rose for the article "U.S. Bombers Are Blasted in Vietnam."
    - The New Republic, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 16: 8-11)
      Includes the November 13, 1961 issue featuring "The Fading Strength of Vietnam"; the May 4, 1963 issue featuring "The Elusive Viet Cong"; the October 12, 1963 issue featuring "Vietnam: What Can Be Done Now?"; and the April 4, 1964 issue featuring "Who's Who in Asia: A Certain Verbal Esprit de Corps Is Discernible."
    - The New York Times clippings, 1965 (Box-folder 16: 12)
      Includes a photograph of Vietnam taken by Rose.
    - The New York Times Magazine, 1962-1965 (Box-folder 23: 4-5)
      Includes the April 25, 1965 issue featuring "Communiqué from Hill 327 at Danang" and the April 8, 1962 issue featuring "The Peasant Is the Key to Vietnam."
    - Newsweek, Vol. 63, No. 12, 1964 (Box-folder 16: 13)
      The cover photo of this issue was taken by Rose.
    - The Reporter, 1961-1965 (Box-folder 16: 14-17)
      Includes the October 12, 1961 issue featuring "The Fight for Rice in Divided Vietnam"; the May 10, 1962 issue featuring "Our Undeclared War in Vietnam"; the January 3, 1963 issue featuring "Burma and the Balance of Neutralisms"; and the March 11, 1965 issue featuring "How Strong is China's Army?"
    - San Francisco Review, Vol. 1, 1960 (Box-folder 16: 18)
      Includes short story "A World of Winter."
    - The Saturday Evening Post, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 23: 6-9)